Inventory of the Slavic Book Dealer Catalogs
Department of Special Collections
- Lozinski, Philip (American branch, Westport, Mass.) [1 of 3], Nov 1962; Sept 1966; 1974; 1979; Jan-March [?] 1985 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  Contains catalogs / price lists, catalog orders, 10 items total, some are slightly damaged. Multilingual.
- Lozinski, Philip (American branch, Westport, Mass.) [2 of 3], 06.08.1987-10.04.1989; n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1)
  Contains correspondence, price lists and photocopies, related materials, 10 items total Multilingual.
- Lozinski, Philip (American branch, Westport, Mass.) [3 of 3], n.d. (Box 40, Folder 2)
  Contains price lists and related materials, 70 items total Multilingual.
- Luch TC (New York - London - Moscow), Autumn 1996; 02.07.1997 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  Contains a catalog / price list, in Russian mostly, and an e-mail printout, 1 page.See: Dr. A.N.Maslov.
- Lukomorye Book Store (Brooklyn, N.Y.), 05.02.1989 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  Contains 3 photocopies of a price list and of related materials. In Russian.
- Magocsi, Paul R. (Fairview, NJ - Cambridge, Massachusetts), n.d. (Box 40, Folder 5)
  Contains 2 typewritten catalogs / price lists, multilingual, and a photocopy of a typewritten price list with handwritten notes, 6 pages, in Ukrainian (Latin transliteration) and English.
- Maisel, Max N. (New York), 1932; n.d. (Box 40, Folder 6)
  Contains 2 price lists, in Russian.
- Maler, Russian Bookstore in Jerusalem, 07.25.1989; Feb-March 1994; n.d. Contains handwritten and typewritten price lists, correspondence etc., 6 items, mostly in Russian. (Box 40, Folder 7)
- Malynowski, R.W. (London), n.d. (Box 40, Folder 8)
- Martianoff, Nicholas N. (New York), 1935-1950 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  Contains catalogs / price lists, 7 items (including doubles); multilingual. Some items with notes and marks and / or damaged.
- Matanię, Radovan I. (Toronto, Canada) [1 of 5], 1999; 05.11.-06.10.1999; n.d. (Box 40, Folder 10)
  Contains correspondence, typewritten or computer-printed catalogs / price lists, including catalogs no. 0-3 / 1999; 8 items total. In Serbo-Croatian and English mostly.
- Matanię, Radovan I. (Toronto, Canada) [2 of 5], July-August 1999 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  Contains catalogs no. 4-13 / 1999
- Matanię, Radovan I. (Toronto, Canada) [3 of 5], Sept-Dec 1999 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  Contains catalogs no. 14-16 / 1999, 18-26 / 1999
- Matanię, Radovan I. (Toronto, Canada) [4 of 5], Jan-May 2000; 2000 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  Contains correspondence, a business card, catalogs / price lists (including catalogs no. 27-32 / 2000); 10 items total. In Serbo-Croatian and English mostly.
- Matanię, Radovan I. (Toronto, Canada) [5 of 5], 2007-2008 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  Contains correspondence and e-mail printouts, catalogs / price lists; 12 items total. In Serbo-Croatian and English mostly.
- Matis (Czech Republic), 1995-1996 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  Contains 2 catalogs, in Czech.
- Matica Srpska (Serbia), Autumn [?] 1996 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  Contains a catalog in Serbian.
- May, Jan (Lebanon, N.H.), 09.17.1982-03.26.1987 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  Contains typewritten price lists and correspondence; some items annotated and / or with handwritten marks / notes / additions. 8 items total, in Polish and English mostly.
- McBlain Books (Des Moines, Iowa), 1981-1982 [?]; n.d. (Box 41, Folder 6)
  Contains 4 catalogs (including doubles), multilingual.
- McCrossan, Brian (Glasgow, Scotland), n.d. (Box 41, Folder 7)
  Contains a catalog, in English and French mostly.
- McGilvery, Laurence (California), 06.24.1997 (Box 41, Folder 8)
- Meeuws, Willem A. (Oxford, OX), n.d. (Box 41, Folder 9)
  Contains a press release, 1 page.
- The Edwin Mellen Press (NY - Ontario, Canada - Wales, UK), 1999-2001 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  Contains 5 catalogs (including doubles), in Russian and English mostly, and a press release, 1 page. Some items are annotated and / or slightly damaged.
- Mercurius Books and Periodicals (Amityville, N.Y.), 1974 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  Contains a typewritten catalog / price list, in Russian (Latin transliteration) and English.
- Metlay, H. (New York), 05.08.1973 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  Contains a typewritten price list, in Russian (Latin transliteration). Slightly damaged.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [1 of 29], 1924-1927 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  Contains 5 catalogs, multilingual. Damaged.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [2 of 29], 1932 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  Contains 7 catalogs, mostly in Russian. Some items are damaged.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [3 of 29], 1933 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  Contains catalogs no. 2, 16, 17, 18 (the front cover only). In Russian and French.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [4 of 29], 1933 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  Contains catalogs no. 21 (2 items), 22, 23, 25, 26 (2 items). In Russian mostly.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [5 of 29], 1933 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  Contains catalogs no. 27-30, 7 items total, including doubles. In Russian mostly.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [6 of 29], 1933 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  Contains catalogs no. 30, 33, 36, 38, 306 (2 items). Most items are damaged / severely damaged. In Russian.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [7 of 29], 1933-1934 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  Contains 4 catalogs (including doubles). In Russian mostly.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [8 of 29], 1934 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  Contains catalogs no. 35-39, 7 items total, including doubles. In Russian. Some items are damaged.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [9 of 29], 1934 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  Contains catalogs no. 40-44, 9 items total, including doubles. In Russian mostly. Some items are damaged.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [10 of 29], 1934 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  Contains catalogs no. 47-49, 51-52, 54, 12 items total, including doubles. In Russian mostly. Some items are damaged.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [11 of 29], 1934 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  Contains catalogs no. 55-57, 5 items total, including doubles. In Russian mostly.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [12 of 29], 1935 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  Contains 6 catalogs, including doubles. Multilingual. Some items are damaged.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [13 of 29], 1935 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  Contains catalogs no. 58-61 (some with enclosed handwritten notes), 7 items total, including doubles. In Russian mostly. Some items are damaged.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [14 of 29], 1935 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  Contains catalogs no. 62-65, 7 items total, including doubles. In Russian.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [15 of 29], 1935 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  Contains catalogs no. 66-67, 69-70, 72 (some with enclosed handwritten notes), 9 items total, including doubles. In Russian. Some items are damaged.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [16 of 29], 1935 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  Contains catalogs no. 73-75, 7 items total, including doubles. In Russian.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [17 of 29], 1935-1936 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  Contains 9 catalogs, including doubles. In Russian.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [18 of 29], 1937 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  Contains 5 catalogs, including doubles, and a photocopy, 1 page, with a handwritten note. Multilingual. Some items are damaged.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [19 of 29], 1937 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  Contains 4 catalogs. In Russian.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [20 of 29], 1937 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  Contains 9 catalogs, mostly damaged / severely damaged. In Russian.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [21 of 29], 1938, 1940 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  Contains 3 catalogs (including doubles), and a photocopy with a handwritten note, 1 page. Multilingual.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [22 of 29], 1947-1950, 1952 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  Contains catalogs and supplements, 15 items total (including doubles). Mostly damaged. In Russian.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [23 of 29], 1983, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 4)
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [24 of 29], 1991, 1994-1995 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  Contains 5 catalogs, some with enclosures. Multilingual.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [25 of 29], 1996 (Box 44, Folder 6)
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [26 of 29], 1996 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  Contains 5 catalogs, one with a handwritten note attached. In Russian.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [27 of 29], 1997 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  Contains 3 catalogs with handwritten notes. In Russian.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [28 of 29], 1999 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  Contains 2 catalogs. In Russian mostly.
- Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (Moscow) [29 of 29], n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1)
  Contains 10 catalogs, some are slightly damaged. In Russian mostly.
- Micro Photo Division (Wooster, Ohio), May 1969 (Box 45, Folder 2)
- Microfilm Corporation of North America (QC, Canada), Fall 1987 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  Contains a catalog / price list, in Russian (Latin transliteration).
- Microfilm / Xerography,1971 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  Contains a catalog with enclosure, multilingual, with numerous handwritten marks / notes. Slightly damaged.
- Middle EurAsian Books (Ontario), March 1998; Aug-Nov 1999 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  Contains 2 price lists, in Russian (Latin transliteration) and English; an e-mail printout, 1 page, and a typewritten letter w/handwritten signature, 1 page.
- MIF Production, August 14, 2000 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  Contains a catalog / price list, 109 pages, a letter, 1 page, and a posted envelope. In Russian.
- Mike's Productions (New York), n.d. (Box 45, Folder 7)
  Contains a price list and a press release, 1 page. In Russian mostly.
- Minters, Arthur H., Booksellers, Winter 1984/85 - April 2-4, 1987; n.d. (Box 45, Folder 8)
  Contains 5 catalogs / price lists, multilingual.
- MIPP International, Inc., Spring-Summer 2000; n.d. (Box 45, Folder 9)
  Contains a catalog / price list and a press release. In Russian and English.
- Miscellaneous materials, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 10)
  Contains miscellaneous press releases, lists of dealers, clippings, photocopies of clippings, etc. Multilingual.
- Mladost (Zagreb, Yugoslavia), n.d. (Box 45, Folder 11)
  Contains a catalog in Serbo-Croatian and English mostly.
- Mlynarski, Bronislaw, Antiquarian Bookseller, 1961 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  Contains a catalog / price list, multilingual, damaged.
- MK-Periodika (Moscow), n.d. (Box 45, Folder 13)
  Contains 2 press releases, one is partially in Russian.
- Moe's Books (Berkeley, California), 12.19.2004; n.d. (Box 45, Folder 14)
  Contains price lists and related materials, 5 items total, some with handwritten notes / marks. In Russian (Latin transliteration) and English.
- Monad Press, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 15)
  Contains a press release / price list.
- Moskovskaia sinodal'naia tipographiia (Moscow), 1913 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  Contains a catalog, in Russian (pre-1917 spelling), severely damaged.
- Moskovskii Patriarkhat - Sinodal'naia Biblioteka (Moscow), Oct 1993 [?] (Box 45, Folder 17)
  Contains a typewritten list with handwritten signature, notes etc. In Russian and English. Slightly damaged.
- Moscow Independent Press Publishing Company (MIPP) (Brooklyn, New York) [1 of 4], 1993-1994 (Box 45, Folder 18)
  Contains typewritten price lists, multilingual, 16 items.
- Moscow Independent Press Publishing Company (MIPP) (Brooklyn, New York) [2 of 4], 1996 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  Contains catalogs / price lists, multilingual, 7 items.
- Moscow Independent Press Publishing Company (MIPP) (Brooklyn, New York) [3 of 4], 1997-1998 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  Contains catalogs / price lists, 8 items.
- Moscow Independent Press Publishing Company (MIPP) (Brooklyn, New York) [4 of 4], n.d. (Box 46, Folder 2)
  Contains catalogs / price lists, 11 items.
- Moskva - Ierusalim (Moscow - Jerusalem"), 1986-1987 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  Contains catalogs / price lists, 8 items (including doubles). In Russian.
- Mouette Press, Autumn 1973 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  Contains 2 identical typewritten catalogs / price lists, in Russian (Latin transliteration) and English, with handwritten notes / marks.
- Mouton Publishers ("Mouton and Co.", Paris - La Haye) [1 of 2], 1964 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  Contains a catalog, in Russian, French, and English.
- Mouton Publishers ("Mouton and Co.", Paris - La Haye) [2 of 2], 1970, 1976-1980, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  Contains 4 catalogs, some with handwritten notes / marks, multilingual.
- N and N Books International, 1994, 1996-1998; n.d. (Box 46, Folder 7)
  Contains catalogs and price lists, 7 items total, in Russian mostly.
- 'Nauka-Export' Foreign Trade Company ("Russian Academy of Sciences Firm 'Nauka-Export"), 1996-1997 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  Contains 3 catalogs with enclosures (press releases, receipts etc.). In Russian mostly.
- National Commission for Statistics (Romania), 1993 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  Contains a catalog with a handwritten note attached. In English.
- The National Library in Warsaw (Poland), 1998 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  Contains a leaflet in English.
- The National Library of Serbia [1 of 2], 1990-1991 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  Contains 2 catalogs, in Serbo-Croatian.
- The National Library of Serbia [2 of 2], 2000-2001 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  Contains 3 computer printouts.
- National Museum in Prague (Czech Republic), 2000 [?] (Box 47, Folder 2)
  Contains 2 computer printouts with attached handwritten notes.
- Naukova dumka (Kyiv [Kiev], Ukraine), 1999 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  Contains a catalog in Ukrainian and Russian.
- Národní knihovna České Republiky (National Library of the Czech Republic), n.d. [after 2000] (Box 47, Folder 4)
- Národní knihovna v Praze (National Library in Prague, Czech Republic), 1991 (Box 47, Folder 5)
- A.Neimanis Buchvertrieb (München, Germany), 1976-1977; 1979-1980; 1985-1986; Nov 1990; June/July 1991; April/May 1992 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  Contains 12 catalogs, multilingual (in Russian mostly), some with handwritten marks and/or library book request forms attached.
- Nej (Prague, Czech Republic), 1994 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  Contains a catalog in Czech (mostly), German, and English.
- Neustein, E. (Tel-Aviv, Israel), 1994 [?] (Box 47, Folder 8)
  Contains a catalog, in Polish. See also: Księgarnia Polska (Polish Bookstore).
- New Books from Croatia, Jan 2002 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  Contains a price list in Serbo-Croatian.
- Nijhoff, Martinis, Book dealers (Hague, Netherlands) [1 of 12], 1968-1969; 1974; 1977-1978 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  Contains 4 catalogs with handwritten marks / notes, some are damaged and/or handwritten notes attached.
- Nijhoff, Martinis, Book dealers (Hague, Netherlands) [2 of 12], 1979-1980 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  Contains 10 catalogs (including doubles), some with handwritten marks / notes and/or handwritten notes attached. In Russian and English mostly.
- Nijhoff, Martinis, Book dealers (Hague, Netherlands) [3 of 12], 1980-1981 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  Contains 12 catalogs (including doubles), some with library book request forms, handwritten notes, and/or business cards attached or enclosed; some annotated. In Russian and English mostly.
- Nijhoff, Martinis, Book dealers (Hague, Netherlands) [4 of 12], 1982 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  Contains 4 catalogs. In Russian and English mostly.
- Nijhoff, Martinis, Book dealers (Hague, Netherlands) [5 of 12], 1983 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  Contains 4 identical catalogs (no.1), typewritten correspondence, related materials. 9 items total. In Russian (Latin transliteration) and English mostly.
- Nijhoff, Martinis, Book dealers (Hague, Netherlands) [6 of 12], 1983 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  Contains 5 identical catalogs (no.2). In Russian (Latin transliteration) and English mostly.
- Nijhoff, Martinis, Book dealers (Hague, Netherlands) [7 of 12], 1983 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  Contains 3 identical catalogs (no.3), some with handwritten marks / notes. In Russian (Latin transliteration) and English mostly.
- Nijhoff, Martinis, Book dealers (Hague, Netherlands) [8 of 12], 1983 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  Contains 5 identical catalogs (no.4), some with handwritten marks / notes, and a typewritten letter, 1 page. In Russian (Latin transliteration) and English mostly.
- Nijhoff, Martinis, Book dealers (Hague, Netherlands) [9 of 12], 1985-1986; 1988; 05.17.1994 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  Contains catalogs, correspondence, and related materials. 11 items total (including doubles). In Russian (Latin transliteration) and English mostly.
- Nijhoff, Martinis, Book dealers (Hague, Netherlands) [10 of 12], n.d. (Box 48, Folder 7)
  Contains 9 catalogs, some with handwritten marks / notes. In Russian (both original and in Latin transliteration) and English mostly.
- Nijhoff, Martinis, Book dealers (Hague, Netherlands) [11 of 12], n.d. (Box 48, Folder 8)
  Contains 8 catalogs, some with handwritten marks / notes. In Russian (both original and in Latin transliteration) and English mostly.
- Nijhoff, Martinis, Book dealers (Hague, Netherlands) [12 of 12], n.d. (Box 48, Folder 9)
  Contains 4 catalogs (including doubles), some with handwritten marks / notes. In Russian (both original and in Latin transliteration) and English mostly.
- NIP Jugoslavija EKO (Belgrade, Serbia), n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1)
- Non Fictio No.1 (Moscow), 12.1-5.1999 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  Contains an exhibition catalog and a press release by the firm "Ekspo-Park Vystavochnye proekty", in Russian and English.
- North Star Books (Montreal, Canada) [1 of 2], n.d. (Box 49, Folder 3)
  Contains typewritten price lists, 44 items, multilingual, some with handwritten notes / marks.
- North Star Books (Montreal, Canada) [2 of 2], Feb 24-July 25, 1986; n.d. (Box 49, Folder 4)
  Contains typewritten price lists, correspondence, and an obituary, 16 items total, multilingual, some with handwritten notes / marks.
- Northern Illinois University Press, 07.21.1999 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  Contains a leaflet-catalog.
- Novash, Michael (N.J.), 1952 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  Contains 2 identical catalogs with handwritten notes / marks, in Russian.
- Novoe russkoe slovo ["Novoye russkoye slovo"] (New York), n.d. (Box 49, Folder 7)
  Contains a release, 1 page, damaged.
- Novum (Warsaw), 1991 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  Contains 2 leaflets in Polish.
- Novyi Mir Bookstore (New York), n.d. (Box 49, Folder 9)
  Contains a catalog in Russian, damaged.
- Nowego Dziennika Księgarnia (New York), 1985-1989; n.d. (Box 49, Folder 10)
  Contains newspapers and a typewritten price list, 8 items total, some items are with handwritten notes / marks. In Polish.
- O'Brien, James Francis (Zagreb-New York), 05.26.1995 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  Contains a printout of a price list and a letter, in English and Serbo-Croatian, 9 pages total.
- Obshchestvennoe mnenie, Fond ["Public Opinion" Foundation], Moscow, 1993 (Box 49, Folder 12)
- Ohio State University, 1999 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  Contains a press release (a printout, 1 page).
- Oldenbourg Akademie Verlag (München, Germany), 09.06.2000 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  Contains a catalog / price list (in German) and a letter, 4 pages total.
- Georg Olms Verlag (Hildesheim, Germany-New York), Spring 1974; n.d. (Box 49, Folder 15)
  Contains a catalog with numerous handwritten marks / notes and a price list. In German.
- Onegin Books (Helsinki, Finland), 03.09.1994 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  Contains a price list in English and Russian (Latin transliteration).
- OPI London ["Overseas Publications Interchange Ltd."], n.d. (Box 49, Folder 17)
  Contains a brochure in Russian and English.
- Orbis Books (London) Ltd. [1 of 4], 1981 [?]-1982; Aug 1986-July 1988; n.d. (Box 49, Folder 18)
  Contains catalogs and typewritten price lists, some damaged and / or with handwritten marks / notes; includes also a letter and a magazine cover. 7 items total, mostly in Polish.
- Orbis Books (London) Ltd. [2 of 4], 1983-1985 (Box 49, Folder 19)
  Contains catalogs and price lists, 9 items total (including doubles). In Polish and English.
- Orbis Books (London) Ltd. [3 of 4], 1986-1989 (Box 49, Folder 20)
  Contains catalogs (some with enclosures) and a photocopy of a price list, 11 items total (including doubles). In Polish and English.
- Orbis Books (London) Ltd. [4 of 4], Summer 1997-1998 (Box 49, Folder 21)
  Contains catalogs, 9 items total (including doubles). In Polish and English.
- Oriental Research Partners [1 of 5], Spring 1971-Spring 1975; 1978-1982 (Box 49, Folder 22)
  Contains 12 catalogs / price lists (including doubles), some with handwritten marks, in Russian and English mostly.
- Oriental Research Partners [2 of 5], 1984-Winter 1986/1987 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  Contains 11 catalogs / price lists (including doubles), some with handwritten marks, in Russian and English mostly.
- Oriental Research Partners [3 of 5], January 1987-Winter 1988/1989 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  Contains catalogs / price lists, bulletins, a newspaper; 15 items total (including doubles), some with handwritten marks, in Russian and English mostly.
- Oriental Research Partners [4 of 5], 1990/1991-1993 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  Contains 4 catalogs / price lists, some with handwritten marks, in Russian and English mostly.
- Oriental Research Partners [5 of 5], June 1994-July/August 1996; February 1998-August 1999; 03.12.-04.01.2008 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  Contains price lists (including doubles) and e-mail printouts, 23 items total, some with handmade marks, in Russian and English mostly.
- Orpan-Export (Warsaw, Poland), 1994-1995; 2001 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  Contains 2 catalogs in Polish.
- Osrodek kultury Polskiej nad Renem (Bonn, Germany), 1984/1985 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  Contains a catalog in Polish and German.
- Ossolineum (Warsaw, Poland) [1 of 2], 1989; n.d. (Box 50, Folder 7)
  Contains catalogs, PR and related materials, in Polish mostly, 26 items total.
- Ossolineum (Warsaw, Poland) [2 of 2], 1990-1991 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  Contains 4 catalogs and a typewritten price lists, in Polish and English.
- The Owl at the Bridge / Samuel J. Hough (Cranston, R.I.), n.d. (Box 50, Folder 9)
  Contains a typewritten press release with a sketch.
- Oxus Books - "Oriental Booksellers" (London), July 17, 1987 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  Contains a catalog with handwritten notes / marks, library book request forms and related documents.
- Pannonia Books (Toronto, Ontario, Canada), 1985, 1993-1998 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  Contains catalogs and a typewritten price list, 13 items total, in Hungarian and English mostly.
- Panorama (Almanac Enterprises, Inc., Los Angeles), n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1)
  Contains PR materials in Russian and English, 5 items.
- Panorama, Informatsionno-ekspertnaia gruppa (Moscow), 1991-1993 (Box 51, Folder 2)
- Panorama of Russia (Somerville, MA) [1 of 6], July 1993-Aug 1994 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  Contains catalogs and related materials (order forms etc.), in Russian (both Cyrillic original and Latin transliteration) and English mostly. Includes "Panorama of Russia" issues (no. 22-24) and the "Current Russian Press" issue, vol. 1, no.1; 7 items total (including doubles).
- Panorama of Russia (Somerville, MA) [2 of 6], 1995-1996 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  Contains "Panorama of Russia" issues (no. 27, 28-1, 28-2, 30-1, 30-3); a yearly catalog without a number.
- Panorama of Russia (Somerville, MA) [3 of 6], 03.07.1997-1999 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  Contains typewritten price lists and related correspondence, 4 items total.
- Panorama of Russia (Somerville, MA) [4 of 6], n.d. (Box 51, Folder 6)
  Contains 2 catalogs, no. 31-32
- Panorama of Russia (Somerville, MA) [5 of 6], n.d. (Box 51, Folder 7)
  Contains 3 catalogs, including doubles, no. 33-34
- Panorama of Russia (Somerville, MA) [6 of 6], n.d. (Box 51, Folder 8)
  Contains catalogs, no. 35, 40.
- Parnassus Book Service (Yarmouthport, Mass.), n.d. (Box 51, Folder 9)
  Contains 5 catalogs, multilingual.
- Pavlin / "Le Paon" (Paris), 1928 [?] (Box 51, Folder 10)
  Contains a catalog in Russian (old spelling).
- Peet, Jan (Bussum, Holland), n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1)
  Contains catalogs no. 698, 714, 728 (damaged), multilingual.
- Pegasus - International Booksellers, Slavic Department (Amsterdam, Holland), Oct 1985-Sept 1994; n.d. (Box 52, Folder 2)